John Vishwas Nelson

... can help you click your way to a beautiful experience

Arlington Heights, IL 60005 johnvishwasnelson@gmail.com +1 469 442 9120

With the passion to go the extra mile and a strong believer in teamwork, I can execute tasks in crunch time with finesse. As a UX designer and researcher, my philosophy for success lies in making an impact through small details.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Sponsorship required to work in the US

Work Experience

UX Intern

Triquetra Technologies - Bengaluru, Karnataka June 2020 to August 2020

- Designed a healthcare app that enables patients to remotely access and schedule healthcare services
- Created wireframes and prototypes for the developer team
- Made creative decisions and setting design standards for the application
- Designed a maternity tracking application for pregnant women

Client Service Representative

University of North Texas - Denton, TX October 2019 to February 2020

- Assisted the design team in editing posters for bringing in more students to purchase meal plans
- Managed production of labels and name tags, for the dining services
- Photographed new food products for campus advertisements

Advisor

Expedia - Bengaluru, Karnataka August 2018 to December 2018

- Resolved problems for client company Expedia(UK) through the International voice processing team that improved customer feedback and ratings
- Gained considerable amount of communication and problem solving techniques by helping customers affiliated with Expedia Air with queries regarding flight and hotel bookings
- Coordinated with the Back-Office to process pending refunds and waivers on flight bookings and cut losses due to third party errors

Education

Master's in Human-Computer Interaction

DePaul University - Chicago, IL September 2020 to December 2022

Bachelor's in Visual Communications

University of North Texas - Denton, TX January 2019 to August 2020

Bachelor's in Visual Communications

Karunya Institute of Technology & Sciences - Coimbatore, Tamil Nadu July 2015 to May 2018

Skills

- UX Design
- UI Design
- Adobe XD
- Sketch
- JQuery
- JavaScript
- Java
- HTML
- CSS
- Adobe Creative Suite
- Wireframing
- Bootstrap
- Layout design
- Python
- R
- Adobe Premiere
- Data Analytics

Links

https://johnvnel.github.io/HCI-422/#

https://johnvnel.github.io/port1/

https://xd.adobe.com/view/b33e06b1-f806-4d4b-a43a-4d86b6b4efd0-e66d/

https://xd.adobe.com/view/da74cacf-5ca9-448a-a910-035ca7450c65-8f27/

https://xd.adobe.com/view/ebc44296-c671-404b-8c2d-e2c74dee229e-be97/

Groups

Student Secretary of Media & Communication Department - Karunya University

July 2016 to May 2018

- Organized and headed inter department competitions
- Assisted professors with the organization of inter collegiate festivals
- Handled cameras and lights for university events off campus

International Student Mentor - UNT

January 2019 to August 2019

- Organized events and activities for incoming international students
- Helped new undergrads and first year graduate students adapt to the new environment through mentorship

Grow Group Leader - Valley Ranch Baptist Church

January 2019 to August 2021

- Mentored middle school kids through Bible lessons
- Actively organized studying activities to help kids learn the Bible better
- Was active in guiding kids through prayer and emotional support